Dan Rosen

SUMMARY

Technical leader with over 15 years of experience in software engineering, management, training and coaching. Recently transplanted back to Boston, and looking to tackle some substantive new engineering problems. Above all, I hope to be part of a team that values learning and collaboration, where I can share my knowledge and learn from my teammates.

SKILLS

Scala: Finagle, Akka, Spray, ScalaTest, ScalaCheck, Scalaz, Shapeless, SBT

Java: Guice, Jersey, Jackson, JUnit, Hamcrest, Mockito, Maven

Other languages: JavaScript (Node.js), Haskell, C/C++

Environments and tools: AWS (Elastic Beanstalk, Lambda), New Relic, Docker, Mesos, MySQL, Cassandra

CAREER

Cimpress · Principal Engineer. Waltham, MA

03.2017 - Present

Designed and built new REST API for access management system, used for authorization by many microservices. Gave presentations on usage and best practices to help evangelize our access management services internally. Reimplemented significant portions of access management codebase for correctness, security and performance. Contributed to internal standards on "service level agreements" for distributed systems.

Twitter · Tech Lead / Engineering Manager. San Francisco, CA

04.2013 - 10.2015

Managed three teams responsible for Twitter's REST API, including auth, rate-limiting and Scala frameworks. Led API monolith decomposition and Mesos migration to improve fault tolerance and developer productivity. Implemented API reliability and performance dashboards, used as a template for all new services. Fixed sporadic authentication outages by porting from MySQL to "Manhattan" (homegrown Cassandra clone). Developed "Scala School" course and taught to all engineers in new-hire onboarding. Provided 1:1 coaching and performance management for 10 engineers ranging from interns to senior staff. Mentored three aspiring junior engineers at Hackbright, a local developer bootcamp for women.

Marakana · Lead Instructor. San Francisco, CA

11.2011 - 04.2013

Taught and coached over 1,000 engineers in person and via LiveLessons (published by Addison-Wesley). Researched, developed and delivered new training courses on Scala, Hadoop and JAX-RS. Modernized Marakana's Java courses, including fundamentals, advanced concurrency and web development. Community events: organized the SF Scala meetup, and production of NEScala 2012 conference videos. Business development: spearheaded Scala training partnership with Typesafe (now Lightbend).

Atlassian · Senior Software Engineer / Developer Advocate. San Francisco, CA

03.2010 - 08.2011

Maintained cross-product plugin SDK and built the "Developer" tab in the Universal Plugin Manager. Designed and built plugin usage tracking dashboard for the Atlassian Plugin Exchange (now Marketplace). Wrote plugin development tutorials, documentation, presentations and blogs.

Coverity · Senior Software Engineer / Sales Engineer. San Francisco, CA

09.2006 - 04.2009

Developed fast virtual function call resolution and checkers for static defect detection in C++ COM code. Designed and delivered Visual Studio and Eclipse IDE plugins, directing a team of offshore developers. Planned and executed technical strategy for major customers, closing over \$1.5 million in product sales. Led training sessions on software quality, static analysis theory, reporting accuracy and other topics.

ANCIENT HISTORY Cloudmark · Software Engineer. San Francisco, CA

AOL Music · Technical Lead. San Francisco, CA

DoCoMo USA Laboratories · Research Engineer (Contract). San Jose, CA

Netscape Communications / AOL · Software Engineer. Mountain View, CA

08.2004 - 12.2005

02.2003 - 12.2002

04.2002 - 12.2002

EDUCATION

Brown University · Providence, RI

09.1996 - 05.2000

Awarded Bachelor of Arts with Honors in Computer Science, May 2000. Received Senior Prize in Computer Science, funded by the William Gaston Premium Scholarship.

Received Honors in Computer Science for thesis work, "Topics in Markup and Software Engineering."